Praveen Kumar

Jamnagar, GJ +91-8200991379, 7089785635 @ er.praveen1782@gmail.com

About Me:

B.E. in Instrumentation & Control Engineering having 10 years, 6 Months of proven experience in Commissioning & Maintenance in the Field of Instrumentation, Having vast experience in Photovoltaic division, Thermal Power Plant UMPP, Refinery Off-gas cracker, Pet Coke Gasification. Commissioning, Maintenance and Troubleshooting of All types of field Instruments, Control valves, FF, HART, ESD (Triconex), DCS (Foxboro), Package system, DCS Tag configuration, Control modification and Cause & Effect testing, Logic Function test. Start-up and shutdown activity of plant

Career Objective:

"To work in a professionally challenging environment to gain hands on experience and to be a Key player in the development of the concern"

Professional Experience:

Manager | Instrument Maintenance

Reliance Industries Limited. Jamnagar, GJ Oct 2016 - Apr 2020 Responsibilities:

- Commissioning and successful start-up and maintenance of Refinery off-gas cracker (ROGC)
 Gas Cracking furnace, Pet coke Gasification (PCG) and Material handling system plants
- Commissioning including verifying Instrumentation activities viz. Calibration, Tube & Cable
 Laying, Instrument installation ITP, P&ID, Hook up etc, Performing Loop checking of Hooked
 up instruments with existing DCS and ESD, Field instruments and control valves
 troubleshooting, System & Marshalling Cabinets Power up activity, Punch point Clearance,
 PSSR, and plant safe start-up.
- Maintenance and Troubleshooting of all the field instruments, Control valves, Foundation Field-bus (FF) and HART Device. Etc.
- DCS (Foxboro) and ESD (Triconex) System related issues Performing Tag Configuration, Control Modification and Cause & Effect testing, Logic function test and Site problem/ failures resolution in safe and efficient manner.
- Handling Engineering Room and Shift activities, PTW, follow-up & co-ordination with other discipline, ensuring safe working conditions & professional manner maintaining high quality of work.

C&I Engineer

Sinofinn Energy India Pvt. Ltd. Mar 2016 - Sep 2016

Responsibilities:

- Worked as team leader for C&I activity of Ash Handling Plant of 6x660 MW Reliance Sasan Ultra Mega Power Project (SUMPP).
- Plan and prepare for breakdown maintenance, modification work, regular maintenance work of different type of Field instruments, valves of AHP, ESP area, SILO, Troubleshooting of PLC's and related issues,
- Maintain field instruments using sound preventive maintenance practices. Ensuring safe working conditions & professional manner maintaining high quality of work.

Commissioning Engineer C&I

ANI Instrumentation Ltd.

Dec 2013 - Mar 2015

Responsibilities:

- Customer site: Reliance Sasan Ultra Mega Power Project, 3960 MW (6*660 MW UMPP)
- Active involvement in start-up activities, Supercritical Furnace Light-up, Steam Blowing, Synchronization and subsequently 72 Hrs. trial run for COD completion Successfully for 6 units each of 660 MW.
- Performing Calibration, Testing, Commissioning, Checking I/O List, Cable Termination, P&ID analysis, Cold/Hot loop checking during commissioning. troubleshooting & Maintenance of DCS, PLC etc, System & Marshalling Cabinets, Field Instruments, Control Valves, Actuators, Coal & Flame Scanner, Igniters etc. of BTG & BOP Area and Pull Cord, Belt Sway, ZSS, Belt Weigher, Coal Sensor, Bunker Level Transmitter, etc of CHP Area.
- Creating and carrying out test procedures, ensuring that equipment works to its specification.

> Engineer | Maintenance

Moser Baer India Ltd. Gr. Noida Jul 2009 - May 2013

Responsibilities:

 Responsible for shift day to day breakdown maintenance & troubleshooting, maintenance in Photovoltaic Division for different types of Electrical, electronics & pneumatic control equipments and all other VFD's, PC, PLC controlled & SCADA based Automatic equipments, Conveyor, PVD, PECVD, Laser Scribing, Material handling Robot (KUKA-KRC2 and Diahan-Z2)

Service Engineer

Life Line Electrical Pvt. Ltd. New Delhi Apr 2008 – Jul 2009

Responsibilities:

• Fault Diagnosis, troubleshooting & repairing of PLC, AC Drives industrial automation products of Schneider Electric.

Education:

- B.E (Instrumentation & Control Engineering.) with aggregate 64.16% from TRUBA Institute of Engineering & Information Technology Bhopal, Affiliated to RGPV in 2007
- HSC from Kendriya Vidyalaya Shaktinagar dist. Sonebhadra (U.P.) with 58%.
- SSC from Kendriya Vidyalaya Shaktinagar, dist. Sonebhadra (U.P.) with 53.8%

Personal Profile:

• Name: Praveen Kumar

• Father's Name: Bhola Vishwakarma

• Date of Birth: 05th Dec. 1982

Sex: MaleMarital status: Married

• Com. Address: Flat No. 302, Jalaram Residency , Opp. BSNL P&T Colony, Patel

colony-6, Jamnagar-361008, GJ

Declaration: - I hereby declare that all the info	rmation stated in this resume is true to the best of
my knowledge and belief till date	
Date:	(Praveen Kumar)